Shiv Shankar

Full stack developer (Python, Node.js, React, PostgreSQL, DevOps and AWS)

As a battle-tested full stack developer with over 15 years of relentless software development experience across the spectrum - from high-octane startups like Intropic to global titans such as HSBC, Citi, Credit Suisse, Barclays and Infosys - I wield expertise in Python, Node.js, React, Next.js, PostgreSQL, DevOps, and AWS. I'm not just experienced; I'm a trailblazer leading teams to engineer groundbreaking, efficient solutions that set new benchmarks. My devotion to supreme code quality and unwavering focus on customer-driven projects positions me as the powerhouse your team needs to achieve unparalleled success.



ShivMS.mail@gmail.com



+44 7442 261482



London, UK





in linkedin.com/in/ShivLondon



WORK EXPERIENCES

Intropic 🗷

12/2022 - Present

- I led the full stack development of the <u>Apptropic</u> suite of applications Passive Fund Intelligence, Fund Flows, and Insights, covering all lifecycle phases and managing databases.
- Enhanced process efficiency with CI/CD practices and pioneered micro-frontend architecture for scalable, easy-to-update projects.
- Directed RESTful API creation for seamless integration and excelled in data modelling for robust database structures.

Senior technical lead

Full stack developer

HSBC software development centre

05/2018 - 12/2022

London, UK

- Led the creation of a <u>Digital security platform</u> for retail banking, scaling it across 32+ global markets to boost security and customer confidence.
- I spearheaded the development and deployment of key banking products such as Personal Loans, Home Loans, Credit Cards, Account Opening across diverse markets, including the UK, Hong Kong, Singapore, and Malaysia, tailoring them to meet local regulatory and consumer requirements.
- I managed the full technical delivery of three technical teams, each comprising 5 developers, 5 testers, a business analyst, and a UX designer.

UI architect

Wipro Limited | Client: Credit Suisse, Switzerland

11/2015 - 05/2018

Pune India

- Led the development of a scalable analytics application for <u>Credit Suisse</u> using React, AgGrid, and D3.js for dynamic visualization and data handling, enhancing business decision-making.
- Established best practices for code quality, boosting the app's reliability and facilitating future
- I managed a technical team and took responsibility for its technical delivery.

Technical lead

Citibank 🗷 08/2013 - 11/2015

Pune, India

- Led the launch of advanced mobile and web applications for Citi private banking, utilizing Ext.is and Sencha Touch, markedly improving the digital banking interface for seamless service.
- Led the redesign and development of a custom presentation layer for Citi private banking.

Full stack developer

Siemens 🗷

02/2012 - 08/2013

 I played a key role as a full stack developer on the Active-workspace project, which serves as an internal StackOverflow for social collaborations and knowledge sharing.

Senior software engineer

Infosys 🗷

12/2008 - 04/2011

- Spearheaded the development of a master data management application for LexisNexis, enhancing their data harmonisation, storage, and retrieval capabilities across systems.
- My role spanned the entire project lifecycle, from requirements to coding, unit testing, support, establishing a solid platform for the organization's critical data management.



EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering VTU, Belgaum, India.

06/2004 - 06/2008



CERTIFICATES

AWS certified solution architect associate (08/2021)



TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend - React.js & Next.js

TypeScript, React Native, MUI, Jest, Playwright, HTML5, CSS3 & Tailwind.

Backend - Python & Node.js

FastAPI, Django, SQLModel, SqlAlchemy, Polars, Pandas, Pytest, Express.js, Nest.js, typeORM & GraphQL.

Databases

PostgreSQL, MongoDB & MySQL.

Terraform, Docker, Kubernetes & Git.

Cloud platforms

AWS & Microsoft Azure.

Development Processes

TDD, TBD & Pair Programming.



AWARDS

Inspiring Performance in the esteemed category of Going Beyond Deliverables award. (06/2016)

Wipro Ltd | Client: Credit Suisse

Outstanding team award (09/2019)

HSBC | Technology



Open Water Swimming

Yoga